Samuel Gustavo Ruiz Torres

JavaScript | React JS | Web Developer | User Interface / User Experience Modesto, CA, 95351 | (209) 809-9422 | sruiz7@csustan.edu

SUMMARY

Adaptable Computer Science major currently attending California State University Stanislaus, with 7+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of Javascript, React, agile development, and communication skills to successfully fill React JS developer position. Frequently praised as hard-working by my peers, and can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

EDUCATION

CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY STANISLAUS

Turlock, CA

B.S. Computer Science Candidate (Expected graduation May 2020)

- Award And Honor: Best Mobile App (Snap Shop) HACKMerced Hackathon, Best use of Snap Kit (Green Gene) HACKMerced Hackathon, Best Domain Name (Turlock Pot Holes) StanHACKS Hackathon, Student Leadership Awards Nominee for Computer Science Club
- Extracurricular Activity: Developer Student Club @ CSU Stanislaus Treasurer & Board Member

EXPERIENCE

Novo Technologies Modesto, CA

Font-End Developer & UI/UX Intern

Nov 2019 – Present

- Overhauling the UI/UX of a production application using Adobe XD which accelerated user's turnaround time by 200%.
- Incorporating the React front-end library and other modern technologies to implement my UI/UX design for a production application which improved the scalability of the project tremendously.
- Drafting user stories, flowcharts, personas, tasks, and sprint backlogs for our scrum sprints that increased my team's productivity whenever we receive adjustments form business.

Google Developer Group Cloud Turlock

Turlock, CA

Organizer

Jan 2018 – Present

- Building relationships with sponsors and co-organizers to plan scope and format of events, to establish and monitor budgets, or to review administrative procedures and event progress which led to a 4x increased yearly budget for events.
- Conducting technical workshops where students learn cutting edge computer science topics and technologies that aren't taught in our campus's classes which reinforced my own computer science skills greatly.
- Building a welcoming community of Computer Science Students by organizing team building events and increased the overall number of members within the developer group.

T-Mobile Wireless Turlock, CA

Mobile Expert / Sales

Jan 2018 – Jan 2019

- Became part of an invested team that helped our store become the #1 leading store in the district in terms of sales and customer satisfaction.
- Prioritized customer's needs by teaching them all the options our company had to offer and demonstrated a ~90% customer satisfaction score, months after being hired up through my departure.
- Trained to communicate with customers effectively in order to make every transaction, a personal, and unique experience. This effectively led to easily achieving my monthly quotas.

Cloth 5 Inc.

Melbourne (Remote), Victoria

Lead Graphic Designer / Graphic Artist

Aug 2012 – Feb 2014

- Demonstrated my graphic design skills by utilizing the vast Adobe Suite Software, including: Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom, & Dreamweaver in order to ensure graphics were created on a strict deadline basis.
- Achieved the status of Lead Graphic Designer within 3 months of obtaining the position of Graphic Designer Intern.
- Communicated and collaborated with co-workers remotely, across the world in order to discuss the nature of articles and graphics that were needed to be created to best compliment our writer's articles.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

• Spanish Speaker - Conversational, Reading, & Writing

CREDENTIALS AND LICENSES

• California Basic Education Skills Test (Substitute Teaching)

REFERENCES

References available upon request